Guide to the Van Cleef Family papers, 1841-1935
Van Cleef Family papers, 1841-1935
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Van Cleef Family Papers, 1841-1935
3088
Van Cleef Family
34.6 cubic ft.
Correspondence, documents, photographs, scrapbooks
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Business and personal correspondence, briefs, legal materials, photographs, scrapbooks, newspaper articles, daybooks and a variety of documentation
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Mynderse Van Cleef was born in Seneca Falls, NY on August 29, 1853. His father and mother were Alexander and Jane E. Van Cleef. Mynderse's great-grandfather was Lawrence Van Cleef, the first white child born in Seneca Falls. As a young man, Mynderse Van Cleef studied at the Ithaca Academy and was a proud 1874, graduate of Cornell University. He went on to study law at Columbia University from 1875-1876 and was admitted to the bar in 1876. On Dec. 21, 1882 he married Elizabeth Lovejoy Treman. Arthur B. Treman, Charles E. Treman, Robert E. Treman and Allan H. Treman were all Elizabeth?s nephews. Elizabeth and Mynderse had two daughter?s Jeannette Van Cleef Booth who married Arthur W. Booth and Eugenia Van Cleef. Both daughters graduated from Ithaca High School. Eugenia went on to attend Vassar College after graduating in 1904. For many years M. Van Cleef and his family lived on University Avenue, in Ithaca, NY. A prominent lawyer, Mr. Van Cleef served as commissioner of the U.S. Circuit Court, 1880-1900. In 1881 Mynderse was named an alumni Cornell Trustee. Among his other achievements he was president of the Ithaca Trust Company as well as chairman of the board. He was director of Tompkins County National Bank and Trustee of the Ithaca Savings Bank. For many years he was the Cornell University attorney. He was also president of the Corporate Association of Kappa Alpha fraternity. Mynderse and his family were members of the First Presbyterian Church, of Ithaca, NY. Mynderse was a member of the Ithaca Fire Department or Protective Police. He was also an officer of the Lyceum Theater Company that was erected in 1893, in Ithaca, NY.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The papers of the Van Cleef family of Ithaca, New York, include a history of Jan Van Cleef and his descendents (1909). Financial records and contracts of Alexander Van Cleef the father of Mynderse Van Cleef are contained within this collection. Most of the Van Cleef family papers contain Mynderse?s correspondence, briefs, Supreme Court documents, court case materials, agreements, accounts, memorandas, printed items, and other materials concerning estate settlements of Joseph Esty, Leonard Treman, Frederick Lovejoy and others, property transferals, and various business concerns, including the Lyceum Theatre Company, the Ithaca Independent Telephone Company, the Ulysses Light Company of Trumansburg, New York, the Ovid Light Company, the Associated Glass and Electric Company, the Cayuga Power Corporation; the Ithaca Street Railway Company, and the Ithaca Water Works, Cayuga Lake Cement Corporation as well as Van Cleef's relations with Eastern investors and Western land agents, his election to and service on the Cornell University Board of Trustees, and his donation of a bandstand to the village of Seneca Falls (1924) as a memorial to Lawrence Van Cleef; Mynderse Van Cleef's notes on Andrew Dickson White's modern history lectures (1872-73) and photograph albums of Cornell students and faculty (1870s); five scrapbooks (1900-1913) of Eugenia and Jeannette Van Cleef containing personal mementos reflecting social life at Ithaca High School and Cornell, and other memorabilia; personal and family papers, including the estate papers of Elizabeth Van Cleef; correspondence, letter book, receipts, and estate papers of Frederick Lovejoy; drawings of Kappa Alpha fraternity; and blueprints. Also, vouchers for construction of the Mynderse Van Cleef family residence on University Avenue, in Ithaca, NY.
Correspondence can be found from Mynderse Van Cleef to Charles Blood, Leonard Treman, C.E. Treman and other important Ithaca businessmen. Letters from Cornell Presidents, Andrew Dickson White, J.G. Schurman and Livingston Farrand are also included in this collection. Correspondence includes letters from M. Van Cleef from Albert Mann, Dean of Cornell University?s College of Agriculture concerning Cornell University court cases. A 1919 letter between Dean Mann, President J. G. Schurman and Mynderse Van Cleef discusses the proposed separation of the College of Home Economics as a separate school within Cornell. A few letters from Martha Van Rensselaer, the Dean of the College of Home Economics can also be found within this collection. Correspondence from Andrew Carnegie, Supreme Court representatives and other government officials are also within this collection.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Van Cleef Family; Esty, Joseph; Lovejoy, Frederick; Treman, Leonard; Van Cleef, Alexander; Van Cleef, Elizabeth Lovejoy; Van Cleef, Eugenia; Van Cleef, Jan; Van Cleef, Jeanette; Van Cleef, Myderse; White, Andrew Dickson; Associated Gas and Electric Co.; Cayuga Power Co.; Cornell University, Board of Trustees; Cornell University, Faculty; Cornell University, Students; Ithaca High School; Ithaca Independant Telephone Company; Ithaca Street Railway Company; Ithaca Water Works; Kappa Alpha Society, Cornell Chapter; Lyceum Theatre company; Ovid Light Company; Ulysses Light Company
Subjects:
Banks and banking; College Students; Education; Electric utilitites; Law and legislation; Estate planning; Investments; Public utilities; Law and legislation; Real property, Exchange of; Street-railroads, New York (State), Ithaca; Women college students
Places:
Ithaca, NY, Social life and customs; Seneca Falls, NY, History
Form and Genre Terms:
Blueprints; Briefs (legal documents); Drawings; Photographs
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. M. Van Cleef's Business and Professional Correspondence
Boxes 1-3, Box 6, Boxes 9-10, Boxes 13-17, Boxes 21-22
Series II. Ithaca Water Works Co.
Box 7
Series III.People of the State of New York vs. Brooklyn Cooperage Co. and Cornell University
Box 7
Series IV. The Estate of Joseph Esty
Boxes 8-9, Box 19 and Box 28
Series V. Ithaca Security Co.
Box 9 and Box 11
Series VI. Mynderse Van Cleef's Court Decisions and Legal Documents
Boxes 11-13, Box 19, Box 23 and Box 35
Series VII. The Estate of Frederick Lovejoy
Box 18 and Box 20
Series VIII.Mynderse Van Cleef and Cornell University
Box 11, Boxes 18-19, Boxes 32-34
Series IX. The Estate of Elizabeth Van Cleef
Box 21
Series X. Mynderse Van Cleef's Personal and Family Materials
Box 11, Boxes 24-27 and Box 29
Series XI. Scrapbooks
Boxes 30-31
Series XII. Alexander Van Cleef's Business and Professional Correspondence
Boxes 4-5 and Box 32
Series XIII. Mapcase
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Mynderse Van Cleef's Business and Professional Correspondence
  - Associated Gas and Electric Company, 1921-1924 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ithaca Trust Company, 1916-1926 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ithaca Traction Corporation, 1918-1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ithaca Traction Corporation, 1918-1922 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Ithaca Street Railway Company (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Cash book (Box 1)
  - Cash subscription to San Francisco Relief Fund (Box 1)
  - M. Van Cleef's personal expenses, 1920-1933 (Box 1)
  - M. Van Cleef's ledger with law business materials (Box 1)
  - M. Van Cleef's bill record (Box 1)
  - 1876 Day book (Box 2)
  - M. Van Cleef's private expenses (Box 2)
  - Estate of Mary A. Cornell (Box 2)
  - Tax letters and statements, 1921-1929 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Ithaca Trust Company, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Morse Stephen" Memorial, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Cornell University Indenture of Trust, Nov. 1925 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Estate of Gustav Ulbricht, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Housing Proposition for Ithaca-Utica Home Mortgaging Company, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Federal Telephone and Telegraph Co.-Ulysses Co-Operative Telegraph Co. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Stewart Memorial Fund, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Farm and Village Telephone Co. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 3 photographs of houses, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper clippings (Jeanette Van Cleef's newspaper contest materials), 1911 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1896-1918 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1912-1918 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1912-1918 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1862-1865 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Cornell Material (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 28 bound paper volumes (not all the same size) of a transcript of a trial before the Ithaca City commission. The case was the City of Ithaca vs. Ithaca Water Works Co., et al., Dec. 1906 (Box 3)
  - Cornell University Class of 1874 reunion, 1933-1934 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Van Cleef Family Genealogy, 1909-1934 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Van Cleef Memorial Library, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Appraisal Information, 1925-1929 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous letters and materials (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous letters and materials (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous letters and receipts (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous letters and receipts (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Mynderse Van Cleef's Supreme Court Appointment, 1895 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Photographs (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Mynderse Van Cleef's Business and Professional Correspondence, Jan.-Feb. 1896 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Mynderse Van Cleef's Business and Professional Correspondence, Feb.-Apr. 1896 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Mynderse Van Cleef's Business and Professional Correspondence, May-June 1896 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Mynderse Van Cleef's Business and Professional Correspondence, June-Aug. 1896 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Mynderse Van Cleef's Business and Professional Correspondence, Sept.-Dec. 1896 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Mynderse Van Cleef's Business and Professional Correspondence, Jan.-Feb. 1900 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Mynderse Van Cleef's Business and Professional Correspondence, Mar.-July 1900 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Mynderse Van Cleef's Business and Professional Correspondence, Aug.-Oct. 1900 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Mynderse Van Cleef's Business and Professional Correspondence, Nov.-Dec. 1900 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Mynderse Van Cleef's Business and Professional Correspondence, Jan. 1904 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Mynderse Van Cleef's Business and Professional Correspondence, Jan.-Mar. 1904 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Mynderse Van Cleef's Business and Professional Correspondence, Apr.-June 1904 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Mynderse Van Cleef's Business and Professional Correspondence, July-Oct. 1904 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Mynderse Van Cleef's Business and Professional Correspondence, Nov.-Dec. 1904 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Letters written by A. Van Cleef to his son and brother (contained within a bound book) (Box 6)
  - Mynderse Van Cleef's District Court of New York certificate, 1862 (Box 6)
  - Cayuga Cemement Corporation Correspondence, 1915-1916 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Cayuga Cemement Corporation Correspondence, 1919 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Cayuga Cemement Corporation Correspondence, 1919-1921 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Cayuga Cemement Corporation Correspondence, 1903-1905 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous correspondence, 1901-1905 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business documents and letters, 1902-1903 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business documents and letters, 1903-1906 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1905 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1905 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business documents and letters, 1907-1909 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business documents and letters, 1915 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1915 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1915 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1915 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1915 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1917 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1917 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1917 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1917 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1917 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1917 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1917 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1917 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business related documents, 1896-1917 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1884-1903 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1884-1911 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous business correspondence, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Miscellaneous record books and documents pertaining to M. Van Cleef's business, 1880-1919 (Box 10)
  - Photograph of a block in Seneca Falls, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous receipts, 1859-1886 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - M. Van Cleef's Business Correspondence to E.H. Bostwick Esq. (A-B), 1894-1898 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - M. Van Cleef's Business Correspondence to E.H. Bostwick Esq. (C-E), 1894-1898 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - M. Van Cleef's Business Correspondence to E.H. Bostwick Esq. (F-K), 1894-1898 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - M. Van Cleef's Business Correspondence to E.H. Bostwick Esq. (L-Q), 1894-1898 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - M. Van Cleef's Business Correspondence to E.H. Bostwick Esq. (R-Z), 1894-1898 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Silas Hewit documents, 1868 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous blueprints, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, Jan.-Feb. 1889 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, Mar. 1889 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, Apr.-July 1889 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, June-Aug. 1889 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, Sept.-Oct. 1889 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, Nov.-Dec. 1889 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1891 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1891 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1891 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1891 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1891 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1891 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1891 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1891 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1892 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1892 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1892 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1892 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1892 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1892-1893 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1893 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1893 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1893 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1893 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - M. Van Cleef's business and professional correspondence, 1894 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, Jan.-Mar. 1894 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, Mar.-June 1894 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, July-Sept. 1894 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, Oct.-Dec. 1894 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1895 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1895 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1895 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1895 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1895 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1895-1897 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1897-1898 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1899-1900 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1901 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1901 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1901 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1901 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1901 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1901-1902 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1902 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1902 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1902 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1902 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence (A), 1903 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence (B), 1903 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence (C), 1903 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence (D), 1903 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence (E-F), 1903 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence (G), 1903 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence (H), 1903 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence (I-L), 1903 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence (M), 1903 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence (N-O), 1903 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence (P-Q), 1903 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence (R), 1903 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence (S), 1903 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence (T-V), 1903 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence (W-Z), 1903 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence (T-Z), 1902-1909 (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence (S), 1902-1909 (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1903-1904 (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence (B), 1904-1909 (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence (C-E), 1904-1909 (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence (F-H), 1904-1909 (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence (I-M), 1904-1909 (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1899-1900 (Box 15, Folder 41)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence (N-R), 1904-1909 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence (S), 1904-1909 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence (S), 1904-1909 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence (S), 1904-1909 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence (T-Z), 1899-1900 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1905-1907 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1906 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, Jan.-May 1907 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, June-July 1907 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, Aug.-Oct. 1907 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, Nov.-Dec. 1907 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1908 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1908 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1908 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1908 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence with the Ithaca Trust Company (A-F), 1909-1910 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence with the Ithaca Trust Company (G-L), 1909-1910 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence with the Ithaca Trust Company (M-Q), 1909-1910 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence with the Ithaca Trust Company (R-S), 1909-1910 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence with the Ithaca Trust Company (T-Z), 1909-1910 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence with the Ithaca Trust Company (A-B), 1909-1914 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence with the Ithaca Trust Company (C), 1909-1914 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence with the Ithaca Trust Company (D-G), 1909-1913 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence with the Ithaca Trust Company (H), 1909-1911 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence with the Ithaca Trust Company (K-L), 1909-1914 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence with the Ithaca Trust Company (M), 1909-1913 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence with the Ithaca Trust Company (P-S), 1909-1914 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence with the Ithaca Trust Company (T-V), 1909-1914 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence with the Ithaca Trust Company (W), 1909-1913 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence with the Ithaca Trust Company (A-B), 1911-1912 (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence with the Ithaca Trust Company (C), 1911-1912 (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence with the Ithaca Trust Company (D-G), 1911-1912 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence with the Ithaca Trust Company (H), 1911-1912 (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence with the Ithaca Trust Company (N-O), 1911-1913 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence with the Ithaca Trust Company (I-R), 1911-1912 (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence with the Ithaca Trust Company (S-V), 1911-1912 (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - M. Van Cleef's business correspondence with the Ithaca Trust Company (W-Z), 1911-1912 (Box 17, Folder 1)